John Parks Whitaker

317-460-0442 johnparkswhit@gmail.com Indianapolis, IN

Objective:

I am seeking a career in software development and web design. I am a career changer, coming from eight years in the consumer banking industry, and having completed Eleven Fifty Academy's JavaScript program, I have obtained the skills to succeed in this new industry.

Education:

- Eleven Fifty Academy JavaScript Certification Indianapolis, IN- Graduated 2019
- Taylor University International Business Upland, IN Graduated 2010

Technical Skills:

Web Skills: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Angular, React **Databases**: Sequelize, Postgres, PGAdmin Node.JS

Deployment: Heroku, Firebase, GitHub

Operating Systems: Windows, macOS

Office tools: Microsoft Office, Apple iWork

Eleven Fifty Projects:

Portfolio: https://johnparkswhit.github.io/

Very early project design for displaying a web designer profile, using HTML, CSS, and very light JavaScript. Includes links to other projects. Helpful to show my development as a coder, as the complexity and quality of my work improved.

Hobbiton HOA: https://jpw-hobbiton-client.herokuapp.com/

React application with a Node.JS server. I created an HOA website for residents of Hobbiton to create user credentials, register their Hobbit Holes, and register mischief complaints akin to a neighborhood watch.

Smart Shopper:

Angular application created as a group project utilizing team Git, Trello, and other team building tools to work together on an overall goal. This application allows a user to log their groceries at home and create shopping list items for the store, all utilizing full CRUD. (This project is not yet deployed but will be by 12/18/19.)

Work Experience

Branch Manager II STAR Financial Bank Noblesville, IN 12/2018-05/2019

- Managed a team in a universal bank setting
- Coached and trained each employee in sales, lending, and operational excellence
- Expanded share of wallet of existing personal and business clients
- Oversaw the operations of the branch to avoid risk and losses to the bank
- Provided exceptional customer service with outstanding survey results

Assistant Branch Manager PNC Bank Zionsville, IN 08/2015-12/2018

- Managed the teller staff to ensure operational excellence and increase sales referrals
- Engaged clients to build PNC relationships in personal and business banking

- Selected for the first ABM Leadership Program for Indiana
- Named to the 2016 Market All-Stars for individual and team performance

Licensed Personal Banker Fifth Third Bank Indianapolis, IN 09/2011-08/2015

- Managed and serviced all account relationships for consumer and business banking clients
- Developed investment opportunities with FINRA licensing to grow revenue
- Drove all new account sales and branch revenue growth
- Consistently scored among the highest in the company in customer experience surveys

Sales Account Manager Verizon Cincinnati, OH 05/2010-09/2011

- Sold Verizon Wireless phones and service plans to customers in-store
- Excelled in a competitive 100% commission environment
- Trained new sales reps and continued as a mentor them once training was complete
- Delivered customer service for concerns on billing issues, malfunctioning phones, etc.

Honors/Activities/Interests

- 2016 Market All-Stars at PNC Bank
- Management Leadership graduate at PNC Bank
- Graduated Magna Cum Laude from Taylor University
- Beta Alpha Epsilon Business Honors Society member, 2008-2010
- Dean's List, 2006-2010
- President's Scholarship, 2006-2010
- Actor in Noblesville and Carmel community theatres

Professional and Personal References

<u>Name</u>	Phone Number	Email Address	<u>Relationship</u>	Time Known
Ryan Blakley	317-529-9836	ryanblakley@gmail.com	Manager at PNC	4 years
Brad Fenton	812-249-9772	bradwfenton@gmail.com	Manager at Fifth Third	5 years
Tony Mascari	317-431-8396	ajmascari@aol.com	Manager at Fifth Third	6 years
Ryan Shelton	317-645-7757	actorryan@sbcglobal.net	Director at the Belfry Theatr	re 7 years
Mark Tumey	317-509-6884	marktumey@comcast.net	Director at the Belfry Theatr	re 7 years

Further References Available Upon Request